[music]
Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we are your
English language guides here at English Pod.
That's right and today we're going
to be taking you to Christmas morning.
It's Christmas Day.
Oh, one of the best
times of the year you wake
up, you smell the good smell of delicious
eggs and bacon and there's presents.
Yeah, I guess that's
when you're a kid though.
I guess when you're an adult, do you really
get excited when you wake up for Christmas?
Hell yeah. Sure do.
Yeah, sure do.
I love Christmas morning even as an adult.
Especially I think
because of the special
breakfast you get like
pancakes, scrambled eggs.
But anyways, we're going
to be taking a look at
a situation here where a
kid is opening Christmas
presents and we are
preparing a meal for Christmas
because that day people
are going to come over.
So let's listen to this
dialogue for the first time.
[Music]
Dad, Dad, Dad!
Wake up!
It's Christmas!
To me, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed.
No way! Santa already
came and left all our presents.
Can we go open
them, please? Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on, get dressed.
Fine, not like Santa brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be
such a grout sometimes.
[Music]
Look at all these presents under
the Christmas tree! Awesome!
All right, Timmy,
knock yourself out.
We should get ready
and head to the market to
buy everything for
Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're
hosting Christmas dinner
at our house so everything
has to be perfect. I got the list right
here. Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes,
ingredients for the
gravy, and of course, yams.
My Dad offered to bring the
eggnog, so we should be set.
All right, we're back,
so there were a couple
of different and
interesting words there,
so let's take a look at them
now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, this first word is
not a very happy word.
It's a word that we
try not to use too much
around the Christmas season, but sometimes
you're just tired of people because
the holidays is all about people.
Yeah, doing stuff, family.
Someone who is not
being very happy, someone
who's a little bit
grumpy is called a grout.
Okay, so the person that's not very
happy, not very friendly, is a grout.
I don't want to open presents.
This is stupid.
Okay, that's a grout.
Okay, so a person is a
grout or you can act
like a grout or be a grout.
Don't be a grout. All
right, and well, they were
talking about heading to
the market to buy something
for dinner, so to head to.
Okay, to head to is a way
to say to go towards some
place or to go somewhere.
All right, so if I'm driving
my car and you ask me where
I'm going, I'm saying, oh,
I'm heading to to the bank.
Right, so to head to means
to be on your way somewhere,
I'm going somewhere.
It's a way to say that
you're in the process
of going. You can't say
next year, I will
head to Alaska. Okay.
It doesn't make as much
sense. You usually say,
I'm, you know, I'm
heading to the bank or it's
head to the market.
Okay, and well, they were
talking about heading
to the market because
they are hosting
Christmas dinner. So to host.
To host is, well, it's a very
important holiday term.
It's a verb. You do
it. And it means that
you were the person who
has the special dinner and
your friend and family,
they come to your house.
Okay. Okay, so we could
say this Christmas, I'm
hosting the dinner
at my house. Okay.
So I want everyone to come
to my house and eat. All right.
And it can also
be a noun, right?
You can say, I am a host.
Exactly. And the host of this dinner.
Right. And it doesn't
have to be holidays,
either you could say,
Hey, Marco, how about you
host a dinner next week?
I'll come. Right. Okay.
Popping wine. All right.
So to host a dinner or
to host a party, etc.
And our fourth word for
language takeaway is
probably the most popular
drink during the
Christmas season egg nog.
Okay. It sounds
kind of disgusting.
Yeah, a drink with egg. But it's a
very popular creamy, eggy drink.
It's very thick and
it's cream colored.
And normally you
add a little bit of rum.
Okay. So it's alcoholic.
Yeah. And you drink it warm.
And it's kind of just a thick, warm,
alcoholic beverage that's very, very popular.
And my dad loves it
during Christmas, right?
During Christmas, you don't
have it like any other day.
No, you wouldn't
want to. It's too heavy.
But it's very, very popular
like the days before
Christmas and on
Christmas. Okay. So egg nog,
very good. So I think
we should take a look at
the dialogue again. And
we'll be back soon with
fluency builder dad,
dad, dad wake up.
It's Christmas to me. It's
too early for this. Look,
it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed. No way.
Santa already came
and left all our presents.
Can we go open
them, please, please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on. Get dressed.
Fine. Not like Santa
brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be
such a grout sometimes.
Look at all these presents
under the Christmas tree.
Awesome. All right,
Timmy, knock yourself out.
We should get ready
and head to the market to
buy everything for
Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're
hosting Christmas dinner
at our house. So everything
has to be perfect. I
got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes,
ingredients for the gravy
and of course, yams. My dad offered to
bring the egg nog, so we should be set.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a
look at a couple of
phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay,
so this first phrase is
a phrase that I often
heard as a child because
I never wanted to go to
sleep. So I'd go downstairs
and then my parents
would say, Katherine,
go back to bed. Go back to
bed. Okay, go back to bed.
So this is just a very
common colloquial
spoken way of saying
go back to sleep.
Go to sleep. Don't be awake.
So you can say go to sleep,
or you can say go to
bed, or if somebody has
gotten out of bed,
you say go back to bed.
Exactly. And so parents
often use this with
their kids because they
want their kids to sleep.
You can also say about
someone who's, you
know, up at night
worrying. You say, come on,
go back to bed. Go
to sleep. Relax. Okay.
And then we also saw this
phrase, knock yourself out.
All right, Timmy, knock yourself out.
So what is this? Knock yourself out.
Well, I'm not really sure
where this phrase comes from.
I mean, to knock is like
to knock on a door, right?
But to knock
yourself out, if I think
about it, it probably
means that you hit yourself
in the head and you fall
over. But the real meaning
of this is go have fun.
Okay. Have as much fun
as you can have. Right.
Have as much fun as you want.
Go knock yourself out.
So the parent is saying,
hey, Timmy, go have
as much fun as you want.
Just go do it. Enjoy
yourself. Yeah, like go open
all these presents. Have
all the fun you want.
All right. And then we saw
another phrase when they
finished talking about
dinner and all the things
they have to buy, they
said, we should be set,
we should be set or
we are set. Well, this is
funny because she says,
well, my dad's going to
bring the eggnog. So
we should be set, which
means we should have
everything we need.
So we don't need
anything else. We're ready.
Everything's good. Exactly.
So we can say, we are set.
Mm hmm. I'm set. Are you set?
Is the way to say, are you ready?
Are you prepared?
Do you have everything you
need? Okay. So I often use this one.
I'm going on a trip.
Right. Are you set?
Did you pack everything?
Are you all set?
Are you all set? Yeah. All
right. I finished packing.
I'm all set. I'm ready
to go. We're all set.
I'm ready to go. All right.
Okay. So some interesting
phrases there as well. Why don't we have
a look at our dialogue for the last time?
Dad, dad, dad. Wake up. It's Christmas. To
me, it's too early for this. Look, it's six
in the morning. Go
back to bed. No way.
Santa already came
and left all our presents.
Can we go open
them, please? Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on. Get dressed.
Fine. Not like Santa
brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be
such a groutch sometimes.
Look at all these presents
under the Christmas tree.
Awesome. All right,
Timmy, knock yourself out.
We should get ready
and head to the market to
buy everything for
Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right. It's the first time
we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
Everything has to be
perfect. I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed
potatoes, ingredients for the
gravy and of course, yams. My dad offered
to bring the eggnog, so we should be set.
All right, we're back. So as
you mentioned, Christmas
morning is great. You
open presents and well,
breakfast and it's time
to be together with
your parents, your
family. But as in this case,
you can be a little bit
of a groutch because
you're just out of kind
of tired because you had
Thanksgiving in November
and then Christmas and
now you're having new
years. So you're kind of just
like, yeah, the holidays
season can be exhausting.
And I know a lot of
families have a special
dinner on the 24th.
That's Christmas Eve.
And then by the time it's
Christmas Day, the 25th,
you're exhausted. You
didn't get any sleep.
You might have had too
much to drink last night.
And so it can be very
tiring also because the kids
always get up way too
early, like six o'clock.
Right. So open
their presents, right?
And then they'll be playing
with their toys all day and you'll
be, you'll have a headache. But it's a
great season to spend time with the family.
And well, we want to know how
you spend your Christmas Eve
and your Christmas morning.
So why don't you come to
our website, englishpod.com and leave
your questions and comments there as well.
We're looking forward
to hearing from you again.
Happy holiday season.
And until next time, bye.